So please finish
Percival for next time.
I know many of you had
this as undergraduates,
but it won't hurt to brush up.
Thank you, Steven.
I also put an advanced
Fourier system
on the main hallway chalkboard.
I'm hoping that one of you
might prove it by the
end of the semester.
Now the person to do so will
not only be in my good graces...
but also go on to
fame and fortune...
by having their accomplishment
recorded and their name printed...
in the auspicious M.I.T. Tech.
Former winners include
Nobel laureates,
Field's medal winners...
renowned astrophysicists
and lowly M.I.T. professors.
Well, that's all.
If you have any questions...
I'm sure that Tom
has the answers.
Hi, Will.
-Kirsten, how you doing?
-I'm all right. How are you?
Good.
I didn't get on
Cathy last night.
-No?
-No.
-Why not?
-I don't know.
-Cathy!
-What?
Why didn't you give me none of that
nasty little hoochie-woochie...
-you usually throw at me?
-Oh, fuck you...
and your Irish curse, Chuckie.
Like I'd waste my
energy spreading my legs
for that Tootsie Roll dick?
-Go home and give it a tug yourself.
-Tootsie Roll!
T-Toots!
She's missing a tooth, Will.
She's got skin problems.
I don't...
Plus, it's like 5-to-2
Morgan ends up marrying her,
you know what I mean?
There's only so many times
you can bang your
friend's future wife.
It's wrong.
Where you going?
I'm gonna take off.
Fuck you, you're taking off.
It's, like, what, 10:00?
No, I'm tired.
Irish curse?
She don't know.
There ain't no Irish curse.
Out! Stop pressuring me back.
Stop crowding the plate!
Which one will it be?
You're gonna get
charged, you know that?
You think I'm afraid
of you, you big fuck?
You're crowding
the fuckin' plate.
Hey, uh, Casey's bouncing up
a bar at Harvard next week.
We should go up there.
What are we gonna do up there?
I don't know.
We'll fuck up some smart kids.
Probably fit right in.
Ow! Fuckin' punk.
-Oh, what's up? You still tough?
-Come on!
Come on. Come on. That's it.
-Professor Lambeau?
-Yes?
I'm in your applied
theories class.
We're all up at the math
and science building.
Come here.
It's Saturday.
Unless you wanna have a
drink with me tonight.
Maybe.
We just couldn't wait
until Monday to find out.
Find out what?
Who proved the theorem.
This is correct.
Who did this?
Jack?
It wasn't me.
Nemesh?
N-No way.
-Come on, Joey, now!
-Billy, McNamara's up.
Come on, kid!
-Joey, dig it out! Dig it out!
-Son of a bitch!
Bring it down, Mac!
That's how to do it! Attaboy!
Take two, Mac.
Hey, Morgan,
who's the girl with the striped pants?
She's got a nice ass.
Yeah, that's a real nice ass.
Who's the guy she's with?
That fuckin' guinea. I hate that
little bitch. Will knows him.
Yeah, I do.
Yeah, fuckin'
Carmine Scarpaglia.
That guy used to beat shit
out of me in kindergarten.
-That guy?
-Yeah.
Fuck this. Let's get some food.
Oh, what, Morgan, you're
not gonna go talk to her?
Fuck her.
-I could go for a Whopper.
-Let's go to Kelly's.
Morgan, I'm not goin' to Kelly's
just 'cause you like
the take-out girl.
It's 15 minutes out of our way.
What the fuck we gonna do?
We can't spare 15 minutes.
Double burger.
Chuck, I had a double burger.
Would you shut the fuck up!
I know what you ordered.
I was there.
So give me my fuckin' sandwich.
What do you mean, your sandwich?
I bought it.
Morgan, how much
money you got on you?
I said I'd get change
when I get the snow cone.
I said that when we pulled up.
Give me my sandwich
and stop bein' a prick.
All right, well, give
me your fuckin' 16 cents
that you got on you now.
We'll put your fuckin'
sandwich on lay-away.
Here we go.
Keep it right up here for ya.
We'll put you on a program.
Every day you come in
here with your six cents.
At the end of the week,
you get your sandwich.
Are you gonna be an ass hole?
What am I, fuckin'
sandwich welfare?
I think you should establish
a good line of credit.
Like how you bought your
couch-payment plans.
Remember how your
mother brought in
ten dollars every
day for a year.
She finally got her couch
Rent-A-Centre style.
Can I have my food, please?
Here's your fuckin'
double burger.
-Whoa!
-Hey, hold up, Chuck.
-Slow it down.
-Who do we got?
-I don't know yet.
-Hey, douche bag!
Yeah, you, you skank face!
Shut the fuck up
-Get outta here.
-What are you worried about?
Why don't you lick
my love stick?
We seen the guy 15 minutes ago.
We should've fight him then.
We're eatin' our snacks now.
-Shut up, Morgan, you're goin'.
-I'm not goin'.
So don't go.
I'm not goin'.
Fuckin' go, Morgan.
Let me tell you somethin'.
If you're not out there
in two fuckin' seconds,
when I'm done with
them, you're next.
Carmine, it's me. It's me, Will.
Remember, we went to
kindergarten together.
-Fuckin', let's go, man.
-Step on his fuckin' head.
Get his ass on the ground.
Stop that mother fucker.
Mother fucker, die!
-Carter!
-Come on!
Will! Will, come on!
Will, come on. Let's go.
Let's go.
Easy, brother, easy.
-Hey, fellas, thanks for comin' out.
-Come here!
Whoa! Whoa!
Ah. Fuck.
Is it just my imagination,
or has my class
grown considerably?
Well, by no stretch
of my imagination...
do I believe you've all come
here to hear me lecture.
Rather, to ascertain
the identity
of the mystery math magician.
So without further
adieu, come forward,
silent rogue, and
receive thy prize.
Well, I'm sorry to disappoint
my spectators, but...
it seems there will be
no unmasking here today.
However, uh, my colleagues
and I have conferred,
and there is a problem
on the board right now...
that took us more than
two years to prove.
So let this be said:
The gauntlet has
been thrown down,
but the faculty have answered
and answered with vigour.
Hey, when's the arraignment?
Next week.
Sorry.
What are you doing?
That's people's work.
You can't graffiti here.
-Don't you walk away from me!
-Hey, fuck you!
Oh, you're a clever one.
What's your name?
Oh, my God.
Looks right.
Will, how retarded do you gotta
be to get fired from that job?
I mean, how hard is it to push
a motherfuckin' broom around?
Mitch, you got fired from
pushin' a fuckin' broom.
I got fired 'cause
management was restructuring.
Yeah, restructuring
the amount of retards
they had workin' for 'em.
Shut up. You get canned
more than tuna, bitch.
At least I got a motherfuckin'
job right now, don't I?
Yeah.
Why'd you get fired, Will?
Come on.
Management was restructuring.
My uncle could probably
get you on a demo team.
Can he do that?
You kiddin' me!
I asked you yesterday
if I could get a job.
And I told you 'no' yesterday.
What's up, Casey?
What's up, Case?
What's up, Big Case?
Let's sit over here.
All right. Let's go.
Oh, this is...
this is a Harvard bar, huh?
I thought there'd be, like,
equations and shit on the wall.
I will take a pitcher of the
finest lager in the house.
Timeout.
I'm gonna have to
bust a little move
on them Harvard hotties
down there at the bar.
Work some magic.
Get some potion for us.
-Oh, hello.
-Hi. How are ya?
-Fine.
-So, do you ladies, uh...
-Come here often?
Do I come here?
I come here a bit.
I'm here, you know,
from time to time.
-Do you go to school here?
-Yep.
Yeah.
That's it. I think I
had a class with you.
Oh, yeah. What class?
History.
Maybe.
Yes, I think that's what it was.
You don't necessarily...
may not remember me. You
know, I like it here.
It doesn't mean
'cause I go here,
I'm a genius. I am very smart.
-Hey, how's it goin'? How are ya?
-Good. How ya doin'?
What class did you say that was?
-History.
-Yeah.
Just history?
It must have been a
survey course then.
-Yeah, it was. It was surveys.
-Right.
You should check it out.
It's a good course.
It'd be a good class.
How'd you like that course?
You know, frankly,
I found that class, you
know, rather elementary.
Elementary.
-You know, I don't doubt that it was.
-Yeah.
I, uh,
I remember that class.
It was, um...
it was just between
recess and lunch.
Clark, why don't you go away?
-Why don't you relax?
-Why don't you go away?
I'm just havin' fun with my new friend.
That's all.
Are we gonna have a problem?
No, no, no, no. There's
no problem here.
I was just hoping you
might give me some insight
into the evolution of the market
economy in the southern colonies.
My contention is that prior
to the Revolutionary War,
the economic
modalities, especially,
in the southern colonies...
could most aptly be
characterized as...
-agrarian pre-capitalist.
-Let me tell you somethin'.
Of course that's
your contention.
You're a first-year
grad student.
You just got finished readin'
some Marxian historian,
Pete Garrison, probably...
You're gonna be convinced
of that till next month
when you get to James Lemon.
Then you're gonna
be talkin' about
how the economies of
Virginia and Pennsylvania...
were entrepreneurial and
capitalist way back in 1740.
That's gonna last
until next year.
You're gonna be in here
regurgitatin' Gordon Wood,
talkin' about, you know,
the pre-revolutionary utopia...
and the capital-forming effects
of military mobilization.
Well, as a matter
of fact, I won't,
because Wood drastically
underestimates the impact of...
Wood drastically underestimates the
impact of social distinctions...
predicated upon wealth,
especially inherited wealth.
You got that from Vickers' Work
in Essex County. Page 98, right?
I read that too.
Were you gonna plagiarize
the whole thing for us?
Do you have any thoughts
of your own on this matter?
Or is that your thing?
You come into a bar.
You read some obscure passage.
Then pretend... pawn
it off as your own.
As your own idea just
to impress some girls?
Embarrass my friend?
See, the sad thing about a
guy like you is, in 50 years,
you're gonna start doin'
some thinkin' on your own.
You're gonna come
up with the fact
that there are two
certainties in life.
One: Don't do that.
And two: You dropped 150 grand
on a fuckin' education...
you could've got for $1.50 in late
charges at the public library.
Yeah, but I will have a degree,
and you'll be
servin' my kids fries
at a drive through on
our way to a skiing trip.
Maybe,
but at least I
won't be unoriginal.
If you have a problem with that,
we could step outside.
We could figure it out.
No, man, there's no problem.
It's cool.
-It's cool?
-Yeah.
Cool.
Damn right, it's cool.
How do you like me now?
My boy's wicked smart.
I just spent three minutes
in this fuckin' place
and run into a Barney, huh?
There it is.
-Nice to meet you.
-They were fine, man.
I was gonna close
the deal, but then...
Chuck... Billy, uh...
insulted one of 'em...
The heavyset girl said I
had a receding hairline,
and I was a few
pounds overweight.
And I was, like,
'Go fuck yourself'.
I swallowed a bug.
Hi.
You're an idiot.
What?
I've been sitting over
there for 45 minutes...
waiting for you to
come and talk to me.
But I'm tired now,
and I have to go home.
And... I couldn't sit there
anymore waiting for you.
-I'm Will.
-Skylar.
-Oh, and by the way,
that guy over there,
Michael Bolton clone...
He wasn't sitting
with us, so to speak.
I know. I kinda got
that impression.
Good. Okay.
Well, I've got to go.
Gotta get up early and
waste some more money
on my overpriced education.
-No, I didn't mean you.
-That's all right.
There's my number.
Maybe we can go out
for coffee sometime.
All right, yeah.
Maybe we can just get together
and eat a bunch of caramels.
What do you mean?
When you think about it, it's
as arbitrary as drinkin' coffee.
Oh. Yeah. Okay.
Uh, right, then.
Oh, come on.
You're kidding.
Yo!
-Fuck you, bitch!
-Fuck you.
There goes them fuckin' barneys
-right now with his skiin' trip.
-Hold on.
We should've beat
that old bitch's ass.
Do you like apples?
-Yeah.
-Yeah?
Well, I got her number!
How do you like them apples?
Come.
Excuse me?
Is this the Buildings
and Grounds office?
Yeah. What can I do for you?
I just need the name of
a student who works here.
No students work for me.
Could you please check?
I have this guy who
works in my building.
-He's about this high.
-Which one is your building?
-Two.
-Two. Building two.
Look, if anything was stolen,
I should know about it.
No, no, no. It's nothing like that.
I just need his name.
I can't give you his name
unless you've a complaint.
This is Professor Lambeau.
And this is Professor Hayes.
Tom, please.
This is important.
Please.
Will didn't show for work today.
Got this job through his P.O.
You can call him.
P.O.?
Yeah, Parole Officer.
Thank you.
Ass hole.
There is a lengthy
legal precedent,
Your Honour, going back to 1789,
whereby a defendant
can claim self-defence
against an agent of
the government...
if that act is deemed a
defence against tyranny,
a defence of liberty.
Your Honour,
Henry Ward Beecher,
in Proverbs from Plymouth
Pulpit, 1887, said
-1887, this is the 20th century.
-Excuse me.
He's gonna make a mockery
of the court room.
I am afforded the right to
speak in my own defence, sir,
by the Constitution
of the United States.
Don't tell me about the
Constitution of the United States.
This guarantees my liberty.
'Liberty', in case you've forgotten,
is a soul's right to breathe.
When it cannot take a long
breath, laws are girded too tight.
-Without liberty, man is a syncope.
-Man is a what?
-Ibid., Your Honour.
-Son, my turn.
I've been sitting here
for ten minutes now
lookin' over this
rap sheet of yours.
I just can't believe it.
June '93, assault.
September '93, assault.
Grand theft auto,
February of '94.
Where, apparently,
you defended yourself
and had the case
thrown out by citing...
'free property rights of
horse and carriage' from 1798.
Joke. January '95,
impersonating an officer.
Mayhem, theft, resisting.
All overturned.
I'm also aware that you've been
through several foster homes.
The state removed you from three
because of serious
physical abuse.
You know, another
judge might care,
but you hit a cop.
You're going in.
Motion to dismiss is denied.
$50,000 bail.
Thank you.
Rise.
-Hello?
-Uh, Skylar?
-Yep.
-Hey, uh, it's Will.
-Who?
-It's Will.
You know, the really...
funny, good-looking guy you
met at the bar the other night.
I don't recall meeting anyone
who matches that description.
I think I'd remember.
Oh, all right, you got me.
It's the ugly, obnoxious,
toothless loser...
who got hammered and wouldn't
leave you alone all night.
Oh, Will! I remember.
How are you?
I was wondering
if you'd call me.
-Yeah, look, I was wondering...
-Yo, what's up, baby?
-Hold on one second.
-What you doing?
Hey.
What's up baby?
Want some of my ass?
Herve, I remember you from juvi.
How you doing?
What you doing?
Oh, yeah, sorry about that.
I was wonderin' maybe we could
get together sometime this week.
Sit out at a cafe. Maybe
have some caramels.
-Oh, that sounds wonderful.
-Yeah?
Yeah, sure. Where are you?
Uh, well, actually, this is just
a shot in the dark, but, uh,
there's no chance that
you're pre-law, is there?
Have a seat.
Thank you.
Nice talking to ya.
What the fuck do you want?
I'm Gerald Lambeau.
Professor you told
to fuck himself.
Well, what the fuck do you want?
I've spoken to the judge,
and he's agreed to release you
under my supervision.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-Under two conditions.
-What are those?
First condition is that you
meet with me every week.
What for?
Go over the proof
you're working on,
get into some...
more advanced...
combinatorial mathematics,
finite math.
Sounds like a real hoot.
And the second
condition is that...
that you see a therapist.
I'm responsible to submit
reports on those meetings.
If you fail...
to meet with any of
those conditions,
you will have to serve time.
All right. I'll do the math,
but I'm not gonna meet
with any fuckin' therapist.
It's better than spending
that time in jail, isn't it?
I read your book, and 'Mike'
was havin' the same problems...
that 'Chad',
the stockbroker, was havin'.
Absolutely right.
Right on the button.
Good for you, Will. Very nice.
Thank you.
Will,
the pressures, and
I'm not judging them.
I'm not labelling them,
but they are destroying
your potential.
No more shenanigans.
No more tomfoolery.
No more ballyhoo.
You're right.
God, I know.
You're not gonna get off that easily.
Come on, Will,
a bit more.
Well, I mean, I do
do things, you know?
What... what kind of things?
I do things that, you know,
I mean, I hide from people.
You hide, do you?
No, no. I mean, I like. I go places.
I interact, you know.
-Really? What sort of places?
-Just certain clubs.
More. That's nice. Yes.
What sort of clubs?
Like, uh, like Fantasy.
Fantasy. That's
nice, a bit more.
It's something like
when you get in there,
the music, like, owns you.
It's like that house music.
It's like...
-You know, you start dancin'.
-Boom, boom, boom. Yeah.
It's just...
Yes.
Do you find it hard to hide
the fact that you're gay?
What are you talking about?
What?
Look, buddy, two seconds ago,
you were ready to
give me a jump.
A jump?
Are you...
I'm terribly sorry
to disappoint you.
Hey, I don't have
a problem with it.
I don't care if you
putt from the rough.
What are you...
putting from the rough?
What on earth are
you talking about?
A difficult theorem
could be like a symphony.
It's very erotic.
You go somewhere else.
I can't handle this.
-Wow.
-Thank you, Henry.
Ah, Henry.
Hi, Gerry.
You know something?
I can't do this pro
bono work anymore.
-It's just not... it's not worth it.
-What happened?
Well, I'm going on national
television next week.
I mean, I haven't
got time to tell you,
much less talk to that
raving looney in there.
An absolute lunatic, he is.
Henry.
Okay, you are in your bed, Will.
Now,
how old are you?
Seven.
What do you see?
Some things in my room.
What is it?
It's like a... it's a figure.
It's hoverin' over me.
You are in a safe place, Will.
It's t...
it's touchin' me.
Where is it touching you?
It's touching me down there,
and I'm nervous.
You don't have to
be nervous, Will.
We...
start dancin' and dancin'.
It's just beautiful,
'cause we...
can make... a lot of love
before the sun goes down.
-I'm sorry, Rich.
-I have better things to do with my time.
Hey. Afternoon delight.
Come on! One dance!
You really hypnotized
me, you know?
For God's sake, Will.
What? Oh, come on.
He left. You can't
pin that on me.
I told you to cooperate
with these people.
-Look... into my eyes.
-Get out, Will.
I don't need therapy.
That's enough. Get out!
I called Mel Weintraub
this morning to see...
Oh, what's the use?
What do you want to do?
-Well, there's someone.
-Who is he?
He used to be my, uh...
my room-mate in college.
Trust.
Very important...
in a relationship. It's also very
important in a clinical situation.
Why is trust the most
important thing...
in making a breakthrough
with a client?
Maureen, stop the oral fixation
for a moment and join us.
Vinnie.
Um...
Because, uh...
Trust is, uh...
trust is life.
Wow.
That's very deep.
Thank you, Vinnie.
Next time, get the
notes from your brother.
If a patient doesn't feel
safe enough trust you,
then they won't be
honest with you.
Then there's really no point
for them being in therapy.
I mean, hey, if they
don't trust you,
you're never gonna get
them to sleep with you.
That should be the goal
of any good therapist.
Nail 'em while
they're vulnerable.
That's my motto.
Oh, good, everyone's back.
Welcome back, everybody.
Hello, Sean.
Hey, Gerry.
Um,
ladies and gentlemen,
we are in the
presence of greatness.
Professor Gerald Lambeau,
Field's medal winner for
combinatorial mathematics.
Hello.
Anyone know what the
Field's medal is?
It's a really big deal.
It's like the Nobel
prize for math.
Except they only give it
out once every four years.
It's a great thing.
It's an amazing honour.
Okay, everybody,
that's it for today.
Thanks. We'll see you Monday.
We'll be talking about Freud.
Why he did enough cocaine
to kill a small horse.
Thank you.
How are you?
It's good to see you.
Good to see you.
-Sean?
-Yeah?
I think I got something
interesting for ya.
What, you have to have blood in urine?
What's up?
Why didn't you come
to the reunion?
You know, I'm...
I've been busy.
You were missed.
Really?
So how long has it been
since we've seen each other?
Before Nancy died.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I was in Paris.
It was that damn conference.
I got your card. It was nice.
-Come here.
-Now that's a take-down.
Hey, what happened?
Did you get leniency or what?
I got, uh,
probation and then
counselling two days a week.
Joke.
You're a smoothie. Come on, Morgan!
Just submit!
Hey, Bill, just...
just get off him. We're
gonna miss the game.
-I've got a full schedule. I'm very busy.
-Sean, Sean.
This...this boy is incredible.
I've never seen
anything like him.
What makes him so
incredible, Gerry?
You ever heard of Ramanujan?
Yeah, yeah.
No.
It's a man.
He lived over 100 years ago.
He was Indian.
-Dots, not feathers.
-Not feathers. Yeah.
He lived in this tiny
hut somewhere in India.
He had no formal education.
-He had no access to any scientific work.
-Coffee?
-You, sir?
-Just a little.
But he came across
this old math book,
and from the simple text,
he was able to
extrapolate theories...
that had baffled
mathematicians for years.
Yes. Continued fractions.
He wrote, uh...
Well, he mailed it to
Hardy at Cambridge.
Yeah, Cambridge, yeah.
And Hardy immediately recognized
the brilliance of his work...
And brought him over to England,
and then they worked
together for years,
creating some of the most
exciting math theory ever done.
This... this Ramanujan...
his... his genius was
unparalleled, Sean.
Well, this boy's just like that.
But he's... he's
a bit defensive.
I need someone who can
get through to him.
Like me?
Yeah, like you.
Why?
Well, because you have the
same kind of background.
What background?
Well, you're from the
same neighbourhood.
He's from Southie?
Yeah.
Boy genius from Southie.
How many shrinks
you go to before me?
Five.
-Let me guess. Barry?
-Yeah.
-Henry?
-Not Rick?
-Sean, please...
, just meet with
him once a week.
Please?
It's a poker game with this kid.
Don't let him know
what you've got.
He probably even read your book,
if he could find it.
It's gonna be hard
for him to find.
-Hi, Will.
-Hi.
This is Sean Maguire.
Will Hunting.
How are ya?
Yeah. Let's get started.
Yeah, let's do it. I'm pumped.
Let's let the healing begin.
Will you excuse us?
Yeah, please, Tom.
You, too, Gerry.
Yeah, of course.
How are you?
Where you from in Southie?
I like what you've
done with the place.
Oh, thanks.
Do you buy all
these books retail,
or do you send away for,
like, a 'shrink kit'
that comes with all
these volumes included?
Do you like books?
Yeah.
-Did you read any of these books?
-I don't know.
How about any of these books?
Probably not.
What about the ones on the top shelf?
You read those?
-Yeah, I read those.
-Good for you.
What do you think about 'em?
I'm not here for a
fuckin' book report.
They're your books.
Why don't you read 'em?
I did. I had to.
Must've taken you a long time.
Yeah, it did.
United States of America:
A Complete History,
Volume I.
Jesus.
If you wanna read a
real history book,
read Howard Zinn's A People's
History in the United States.
That book'll fuckin'
knock you on your ass.
Better than Chomsky's
Manufacturing Consent?
Do you think that's a good book?
You fuckin' people baffle me.
You spend all your money on
these fuckin' fancy books.
You surround
yourselves with 'em.
They're the wrong fuckin' books.
What are the right
fuckin' books, Will?
Whatever blows your hair back.
Yeah. Haven't got
much hair left.
Hey, you know you'd be
better shoving that cigarette
up your ass. It'd probably
be healthier for you.
Yeah, I know. It really
gets in the way of my yoga.
-You work out, huh?
What, you lift?
Yeah.
Nautilus?
No, free weights.
-Oh, really? Free weights, huh?
-Yeah. Yeah, big time.
-Yeah?
-Just like that.
-What do you bench?
-285. What do you bench?
You paint that?
-Yeah.
-Do you paint?
Do you sculpt?
No.
Do you like art?
Do you like music?
This is a real piece of shit.
Oh, tell me what
you really think.
I don't know. Just the...
linear and impressionistic mix
makes a very
muddled composition.
It's also a Winslow
Homer rip-off,
except you got whitey
rowin' the boat there.
Well, it's art, Monet.
It wasn't very good.
That's not really what
concerns me though.
What concerns you?
-Just the colouring.
-You know what the real bitch of it is?
It's paint-by-number.
Is it colour-by-number?
Because the colours
are fascinating to me.
-Aren't they really?
-You bet.
I think you're
about one step away
from cuttin' your
fuckin' ear off.
Really?
Oh, yeah.
Think I should move to
the south of France,
change my name to 'Vincent'?
You ever heard the sayin',
'any port in a storm'?
Yeah.
Yeah, maybe that means you.
In what way?
Maybe you're in the middle of
a storm, a big fuckin' storm.
Yeah, maybe.
The sky's fallin' on your head.
The waves are crashin'
over your little boat.
The oars are about to snap.
You just piss in your pants.
You're cryin' for the harbour.
So maybe you do what
you gotta do to get out.
You know, maybe you
became a psychologist.
Bingo. That's it.
Let me do my job now. You
start with me. Come on.
Maybe you married
the wrong woman.
Maybe you should
watch your mouth!
Watch it right there,
chief, all right?
Ah.
That's it, isn't it?
You married the wrong woman.
What happened?
What, did she leave you?
Was she, you know...
banging some other guy?
If you ever disrespect my
wife again, I will end you.
I will fuckin' end you.
Got that, chief?
Time's up.
Yeah.
At ease, gentlemen.
You okay?
Look, I'll understand if you
don't wanna meet with him again.
Thursday, 4:00. Make
sure the kid's here.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Well, you look lovely
in those glasses.
-Thank you very much.
-They're just beautiful.
Yes, I always wanted
dark blue eye shadow.
Wonderful.
Growing up in England, you know,
I went to a very nice school.
You know, it was kind of...
progressive, organic,
do-it-yourself, private school.
Then Harvard.
Hopefully med school.
You know, I figured
out, by the end,
my brain's gonna
be worth $250,000.
That sounded
horrible, didn't it?
Bring me another mai tai!
Yeah, that's cool.
I mean, I bet your
parents were happy to pay.
No, I was happy to pay.
I inherited the money.
Wow.
Is Harvard gettin'
all that money?
No, Stanford. I'm going there
in June when I graduate.
All right, so you
just wanted to use
this sailor and
then run away, huh?
Well, I was gonna, you know,
experiment on you for anatomy
class first, obviously.
In that case, that's fine.
Hey, you wanna see my
magic tricks, Skylar?
Of course.
All right.
Promise to...
This one's for you, Rudolph.
Wait, wait. You need my wand.
All right, give me a hit.
Thank you. All right.
I'm gonna make all these
caramels disappear.
You ready?
Ready.
One,
two,
three.
They're all gone.
That was my... It works
better when I have my rabbit.
Well...
I don't really date,
you know, that much.
How very unfortunate...
I think for me.
You know what I mean?
I know you've been
thinking about it.
-Oh, no, I haven't.
-Yes, you have.
No, I really haven't.
Yes, you have. You're hoping
to get good night kiss.
No, you know, I tell ya,
I was hopin' to get
a good night laid.
But I'll settle for,
like, a kiss, you know?
-How very noble of you.
-Thank you.
No, I was... I was
hopin' for a kiss.
Well, why don't we just
get it out of the way now?
-Right now?
-Yeah.
Come on.
I think I got some
of your pickle.
You again, huh?
Come with me.
So what's this?
A Taster's Choice
moment between guys?
This is really nice.
You got a thing for swans?
Is this, like, a fetish?
Is it something, like,
maybe we need to
devote some time to?
Thought about what you
said to me the other day.
About my painting.
Stayed up half the
night thinking about it.
Something occurred to me.
I fell into a deep,
peaceful sleep
and haven't thought
about you since.
You know what occurred to me?
No.
You're just a kid.
You don't have the faintest
idea what you're talking about.
Why, thank you.
It's all right.
You've never been out of Boston.
Nope.
So if I asked you about art,
you'd probably
give me the skinny
on every art book ever written.
Michelangelo?
You know a lot about him.
Life's work,
political aspirations.
Him and the pope.
Sexual orientation.
The whole works, right?
I bet you can't tell me
what it smells like
in the Sistine Chapel.
You never actually stood there
and looked up at that
beautiful ceiling.
Seeing that.
If I ask you about women,
you'll probably give me a syllabus
of your personal favourites.
You may have even
been laid a few times.
But you can't tell
me what it feels like
to wake up next to a woman,
and feel truly happy.
You're a tough kid.
I ask you about
war, you'd probably
throw Shakespeare at me, right?
'Once more into the
breach, dear friends.'
But you've never been near one.
You've never held your best
friend's head in your lap...
and watch him gasp his last
breath lookin' to you for help.
If I asked you about love,
you'd probably
quote me a sonnet,
but you've never
looked at a woman
and been totally vulnerable.
Known someone that could
level you with her eyes.
Feelin' like God put an
angel on earth just for you,
who could rescue you
from the depths of hell.
And you wouldn't know what
it's like to be her angel,
to have that love for
her be there forever.
Through anything.
Through cancer.
And you wouldn't
know about sleepin'
sittin' up in a hospital room...
for two months,
holding her hand,
because the doctors
could see in your eyes...
that the terms 'visiting
hours' don't apply to you.
You don't know about real loss,
'cause that only
occurs when you love
something more than
you love yourself.
I doubt you've ever dared
to love anybody that much.
I look at you.
I don't see an
intelligent, confident man.
I see a cocky,
scared shitless kid.
But you're a genius, Will.
No one denies that.
No one could possibly
understand the depths of you.
But you presume
to know everything
about me because you
saw a painting of mine.
You ripped my
fuckin' life apart.
You're an orphan, right?
Do you think I'd
know the first thing
about how hard your
life has been...
how you feel, who you are...
because I read Oliver Twist?
Does that encapsulate you?
Personally,
I don't give a shit about all
that, because... you know what?
I can't learn
anything from you...
I can't read in
some fuckin' book.
Unless you wanna talk about you,
who you are.
And I'm fascinated.
I'm in.
But you don't wanna do
that, do you, sport?
You're terrified of
what you might say.
Your move, chief.
Hello?
Professor Valenti, are
you calling me again?
Freak.
-Oh, God.
-Christ, who did you call?
No one. I forgot the number.
You fuckin' retarded?
You went all the way
out there in the rain,
and you didn't bring the number.
No, it was your
mother's 900 number.
I just ran out of quarters.
Why don't we get off on mothers?
I just got off yours.
That's pretty funny, Morgan.
That's a fuckin' nickel, bitch.
Keep antagonizing me.
Watch what happens.
All right, then, Morgan.
-Watch what happens.
-All right, then, Morgan.
Watch what happens.
Keep fuckin' with me.
No smoking.
What do you mean,
he didn't talk?
You were in there for an hour.
He just sat there
counting the seconds
until the session was over.
Pretty impressive, actually.
Why would he do that?
To prove to me he doesn't
have to talk to me
if he doesn't want to.
What is this? Some
kind of staring contest
between two kids from
the old neighbourhood?
Yeah, it is,
and I can't talk first.
We know your theory, Alexander,
but the boy's found a
simple geometrical picture.
A tree structure won't work.
Look now. He's joining
the two vertices.
But I can do the sum.
It's how you group
the terms, Alexander.
But, Gerry, if we do the
whole thing this way, then...
Hey, look, look.
I wrote it down.
It's simpler this way.
Sometimes people get lucky.
You're a brilliant man.
You know, I was on
this plane once,
and I'm sittin' there, and...
the captain gets on, he
does his whole, you know,
'we'll be cruisin'
at 35,000 feet',
but then he puts the mike down.
He forgets to turn it off.
So he turns to the copilot.
He's, like, 'You know,
all I could use right
now is a fuckin'
blow job and a cup of coffee.'
So the stewardess
fuckin' goes bombin'
up from the back of the plane...
to tell him the
microphone's still on.
This guy in the back
of the plane's like,
'Hey, hon, don't
forget the coffee'.
You ever been on a plane?
No, but it's a fuckin' joke.
It works better if I tell
it in the first person.
Yeah, it does.
I have been laid, you know?
Really?
Good for you.
Big time.
Big time, huh?
I went on a date last week.
-How'd it go?
-It was good.
Goin' out again?
I don't know.
Why not?
Haven't called her.
Christ, you're an amateur.
-I know what I'm doin'.
-Oh, yeah?
Don't worry about me.
I know what I'm doin'.
Yeah, but this girl was,
like, you know, beautiful.
She's smart. She's fun.
She's different from most
of the girls I've been with.
So call her up, Romeo.
Why, so I can realize
she's not that smart.
That she's fuckin' boring?
You know, I mean, you don't...
This girl's, like,
fuckin' perfect right now.
I don't wanna ruin that.
Maybe you're perfect right now.
Maybe you don't wanna ruin that.
But I think that's a
super philosophy, Will.
That way, you can go
through your entire life
without ever having to
really know anybody.
My wife used to fart
when she was nervous.
She had all sorts of
wonderful idiosyncrasies.
You know, she used
to fart in her sleep.
Just thought I'd
share that with you.
One night it was so
loud, it woke the dog up.
She woke up and gone,
like, 'Was that you?'
I said, 'Yeah'. I didn't
have the heart to tell her.
Oh, God.
-She woke herself up?
-Yes.
Oh, Christ.
But, Will, she's
been dead two years
and that's the shit I remember.
It's wonderful stuff, you know?
Little things like that.
Yeah, but those are the
things I miss the most.
Those little idiosyncrasies
that only I knew about.
That's what made her my wife.
Boy, and she had
the goods on me too.
She knew all my
little peccadilloes.
People call these
things 'imperfections',
but they're not.
That's the good stuff.
And then we get to choose
who we let into our
weird little worlds.
You're not perfect, sport.
And let me save
you the suspense.
This girl you met,
she isn't perfect either.
But the question
is whether or not
you're perfect for each other.
That's the whole deal.
That's what intimacy
is all about.
Now you can know everything
in the world, sport,
but the only way you're
findin' out that one
is by givin' it a shot.
You certainly won't learn
from an old fucker like me.
Even if I did know, I wouldn't
tell a pissant like you.
Yeah, why not?
You told me every other fuckin' thing.
Jesus Christ.
Fuckin' talk more than any
shrink I ever seen in my life.
I teach the shit. I didn't
say I knew how to do it.
Yeah.
You ever think about
gettin' remarried?
My wife's dead.
Hence the word 'remarried'.
She's dead.
Yeah, well, I think that's
a super philosophy, Sean.
I mean, that way,
you can actually
go through the rest
of your life...
without ever really
knowing anybody.
Time's up.
-Hold it open.
-Okay.
Thanks.
'G' minor seventh,
saddest of all chords.
-Hello.
-Hey.
Where have you been?
I'm sorry. I've been,
like... really busy, and...
-But, um...
-Me too.
Yeah.
I...
I thought you'd call.
Yeah, um...
I mean, we had a
really good time.
I had a really good time too.
I mean, I just... I...
I'm sorry, you know. I blew it.
No. No, I mean, you
know, it's all right.
Yeah, um, so, I was...
wonderin' if, uh,
if, you know, you'd give
me another crack at it.
You know, let me
take you out again.
I can't.
All right.
Oh, no, I didn't...
I didn't mean I
can't, like, ever.
I just can't right now.
I've got to assign the proton
spectrum for 'ebogamine'.
All that sounds really,
really interesting.
It's actually
fantastically boring.
-All right, um...
-Maybe some other time.
Like tomorrow?
Um, yeah, all right.
-Okay.
-Bye.
What are you doing here?
I couldn't wait till tomorrow.
Where the fuck did you get this?
I had to sleep with
someone in your class.
Oh, I hope it was someone
with the open-toed sandals
and the really bad breath.
Come on. Let's go have some fun.
No, I've got to learn this.
Well, you're not going into
surgery tomorrow, are you?
No.
Let's go.
Oh, my God! My dog is winning!
Come on, Misty!
Come on! Run! Look at that!
Come on!
Look, there he goes. Misty, run!
We won.
He totally won.
So did you grow up
around here then?
Not far. South Boston.
Still glowing from my win.
Look at you. You're so happy.
And what was that like then?
It was normal, I guess.
Nothin' special.
Do you got lots of
brothers and sisters?
Do I have a lot of
That's what I said.
Well, Irish Catholic,
what do you think?
Right. That's right.
How many?
God. You wouldn't
believe me if I told you.
Why? Go on. What? Five?
-No.
-Seven?
Eight? How many?
-I have 12 big brothers.
-You do not!
No, I swear to God.
I swear to God. I'm
lucky 13 right here.
Do you know all their names?
Do I... yeah,
they're my brothers.
What are they called?
Marky, Ricky, Danny,
Terry, Mikey, Davey,
Timmy, Tommy, Joey,
Robby, Johnny and Brian.
Say it again.
Marky, Ricky, Danny,
Terry, Mikey, Davey,
Timmy, Tommy, Joey,
Robby, Johnny and Brian.
And Willy.
-Willy?
-Yeah.
-Will.
-Wow.
Do you still see all of them?
Yeah, well, they
all live in Southie.
I'm livin' with three
of 'em right now.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
I'd like to meet them.
Yeah, we'll do that.
Oh, you know, I read
your book last night.
Oh, so you're the one.
Do you still, uh... Do you
still counsel veterans?
No, I don't.
Why not?
Well, I gave it up
when my wife got sick.
You ever wonder what your
life would be like if you, uh,
if you never met your wife?
What? Wonder if I'd be
better off without her?
No, no, no, I'm not
saying, like, better off.
No.
I didn't mean it like that.
It's all right. It's
an important question.
'Cause you'll have bad times,
but that'll always
wake you up...
to the good stuff you
weren't paying attention to.
And you don't regret
meetin' your wife?
Why? 'Cause the pain I feel now?
Oh, I got regrets, Will, but,
I don't regret a single
day I spent with her.
So when did you know, like,
that she was the one for you?
October 21, 1975.
Jesus Christ. You
know the fuckin' day?
Oh, yeah,
'cause it was game six
of the World Series,
biggest game in Red Sox history.
Yeah, sure.
My friends and I had slept
out all night to get tickets.
You got tickets?
Yep. Day of the game
I was sittin' in a bar,
waitin' for the game to start
and in walks this girl.
It was an amazing game though.
You know, bottom of the
eighth, Carbo ties it up.
It was 6-6.
It went to 12.
Bottom of the 12th,
in stepped Carlton
Fisk, old Pudge.
Steps up to the plate. You know,
-he's got that weird stance.
-Yeah, yeah.
And then 'Boom'! He
clocks it, you know.
High fly ball down
the left field line!
Thirty-five thousand
people on their feet,
yellin' at the ball.
But that's nothin',
'cause Fisk, he's wavin'
at the ball like a madman.
-Yeah, I've seen that.
-'Get over! Get over!
-Right.
-Get over!'
Then it hits the foul pole.
He goes ape-shit,
and 35,000 fans...
They charge the field, you know.
Yeah, and he's fuckin'
blowin' people outta the way.
'Get outta the way!
Get outta the way!'
I can't fuckin' believe you had
tickets to that fuckin' game!
Did you rush the field?
No, I didn't rush the fuckin' field.
I wasn't there.
What?
No, I was in a bar, havin'
a drink with my future wife.
You missed Pudge Fisk's home run...
-Oh yeah.
to have a fuckin' drink with
some lady you never met?
Yeah, but you should have seen her.
She was a stunner.
-I don't care if...
-Oh, no, no, she lit up the room.
I don't care if Helen of
Troy walks into the room.
Oh, Helen of Troy!
That's game six! Oh, my God,
and who were these
friends of yours?
They let you get away with that?
They had to.
What did you say to 'em?
I just slid my ticket
across the table.
I said, 'Sorry, guys.
I gotta see about a girl.'
-'I gotta go see about a girl'?
-Yes!
That's what you said? They
let you get away with that?
Oh, yeah. They saw it in
my eyes that I meant it.
You're kiddin' me?
No, I'm not kidding you, Will.
That's why I'm not
talkin' right now
about some girl I saw
at a bar 20 years ago...
and how I always regretted not
goin' over and talkin' to her.
I don't regret the 18 years
I was married to Nancy.
I don't regret the six years
I had to give up counselling
when she got sick,
and I don't regret the last
years when she got really sick.
And I sure as hell don't
regret missin' a damn game.
That's regret.
Wow!
Would have been nice to
catch that game though.
I didn't know Pudge was
gonna hit a home run.
You know,
I'm very, very useful on the court.
I'm extremely tall.
-You're not that tall.
-I dunk.
Will I ever play in the N.B.A.?
'It is decidedly so.'
Why do we always stay here?
'Cause it's nicer than my place.
Yes, but I've never
seen your place.
I know.
When am I gonna meet your
friends and your brothers?
Well, they don't really
come down here that much.
I think I can make
it to South Boston.
It's kind of a hike.
Is it me you're hiding from
them or the other way around?
-All right, we'll go.
-When?
I don't know. We'll
go sometime next week.
What if I said I would
not sleep with you again
until you let me
meet your friends?
I'd say it's, like,
4:30 in the mornin'.
They're probably up.
Oh, my God.
Men are shameless.
If you're not thinking
with your wiener,
then you're acting
directly on its behalf.
You bet. And on
behalf of my wiener,
can I get an advance payment?
I don't know. Let's ask.
'Outlook does not look good.'
What?
Fuck the... Hey, Chuck. No.
Nothing. Go back to sleep.
'Outlook'? That's the same thing
that told you you was
gonna play in the N.B.A.
Well, exactly, so look out.
You'd better start buying
some season tickets.
I plan to. I'm tall.
I like wearing shorts.
Hook, hook. Dunk, dunk.
-You're not that tall.
-Yes, I am.
Maybe I'm all
about three points.
I'm all about home runs.
Stop mixing your
sporting metaphors.
A leprechaun's got his
dick in the monkey's ass.
Morgan comes runnin' in, goin',
'I don't mind it. I don't mind.'
Well, I can't believe
you brought Skylar here
when we're fuckin' all
bombed and drinkin'.
I know, Morgan. It's a real
rarity we'd be all drinkin'.
My uncle Marty drinks.
He'll go on a bender
for six, eight months.
Did I ever tell ya
what happened to him
when he was drivin' up
there and got pulled over?
-I told you guys, right?
-Marty, yeah.
Let me tell ya what
happened to my uncle Marty,
because you oughta know this.
He's always tellin' stories.
Every time we come here
he's got another story.
But we all heard this one.
Go ahead. Say it anyway.
I will go ahead. Thanks a lot.
Guess I have the floor now.
My uncle Marty's
drivin' home, right?
Bombed out of his tree, right?
Just hammered out of his gourd.
Just wrecked.
This state trooper sees
him, pulls him over.
So my uncle's fucked basically.
Got him out of the car, tryin'
to make him walk the line.
He gets out of the car,
pukes, and the statie's pretty
sure he's over the legal limit.
So he's about to throw the cuffs
on him and put him in jail.
All of a sudden, 50
yards down the road,
there's this huge
fuckin' boom, right?
Statie gets real spooked.
-He turns around.
-He got shot?
No. So... So... You
heard this story before.
Yeah, Morgan, stop. Stop.
Some other guy's
car had hit a tree.
Okay. There was an accident.
Anyway...
-How could he hear...
-Shut the fuck up!
You're drivin' him nuts, Morgan.
I'm gonna break your neck.
Shut up!
He told you the
story once before.
So he tells my uncle, 'Stay here.
Don't move.'
Statie goes runnin' down the
road to deal with
the other accident.
After a few minutes of just
lyin' in his own piss and vomit,
my uncle starts wonderin'
what he's doin' there.
Gets up, gets in his car
and just drives home.
The next mornin' my
uncle's just passed out.
He hears this
knockin' at the door.
So he goes downstairs,
pulls the door open 'What?'
It's the state trooper
that pulled him over.
Statie says, 'Fuck
you mean, 'What?'
You know what.
I pulled you over last night
is what, and you took off.'
He's like, 'I never seen
you before in my life.
I've been home all
night with my kids.
I don't know who
the fuck you are.'
He's like, 'You know who I am.
Let me get in your garage.'
My uncle's like,
'What?' He said, 'You heard me.
Let me get in your garage.'
He was like, 'All right. Fine.'
Takes him out to the
garage, opens the door.
And there's...
the statie's police cruiser
is in my uncle's garage.
He was so fuckin'...
He was so fuckin' hammered
he drove the wrong car home.
The best part about it is,
the fuckin' state trooper...
was so embarrassed he
didn't do anything.
He'd been drivin' around all
night in my uncle's Chevelle,
lookin' for the house.
All right, Chuck, what the fuck
is the point of your story?
He got away. That's the point.
-Well, question...
-Come on. Stop.
-I'm tryin' to clarify somethin'.
-You're embarrassing him.
-It doesn't make any sense.
-It does make sense,
if you listen to the story
and quit askin' questions.
Well, let's see if
you can get this one.
I've got a little story for you.
All right.
There's an old couple in bed,
Mary and Paddie.
They wake up on the
morning of their
50th anniversary.
Mary looks over and gazes
adoringly at Paddie.
She's like, 'Oh, Jesus, Paddie.
You're such a good-looking feller.
I love ya.
I want to give ya
a little present.
Anything your little heart desires,
I'm goin' to give it to ya.
What would ya like?
Paddie's like,
'Oh, gee, Mary. That's
a very sweet offer.
Now, in 50 years,
there's one thing
that's been missing,
and, uh,
I would like you to
give me a blow job.
I would like for it.'
Mary's like, 'All right.'
She takes her teeth out,
puts 'em in the glass.
She gives him a blow job.
Afterwards, Paddie's like,
'Yeah, geez, now that's
what I've been missin'.
That was the most beautiful,
earth-shattering thing ever!
Beautiful, Mary! I love ya!
Is there anything that
I can do for you?'
Mary looks up to
him and she goes,
'Give us a kiss.'
-Oh!
-Oh, my God!
-That's filthy.
-It's not that filthy. I've heard filthy.
Get off of me!
All right. See you guys later.
All right. Take it easy, Bill.
So, Skylar, thanks
for comin' by.
Changed my opinion
of Harvard people.
You don't want to rush
to judgement on that one,
'cause they're not all like me.
Oh. I'm sure. It
was nice to meet ya.
Oh.
Take it easy.
-Oh, come on.
-Slowly back away.
-Brother.
-I don't know what you're doin', dude.
You're givin' us a ride.
What the fuck do I
look like to you?
Come on, Chuck.
You're walkin', bitch.
Will's takin' the car.
All right, thanks, sucker.
I appreciate it.
I don't know what you're
gettin' all serious about.
You're droppin' me off first.
It's really out of the way.
Oh, okay. Just
'cause you don't have
to sleep in your one-room
palace tonight...
don't start thinkin' you're bad.
Hey, wait a minute. You said
we were gonna see your place.
-Not tonight.
-Oh, no, not tonight. Not any other night.
He knows once you
see that shit-hole
he's gettin' dropped
like a bad habit.
But I wanted to
meet your brothers.
We're gonna do
that another time.
All right.
Need them keys.
The stewardess hears this
and goes haulin'
ass down the aisle.
I yell,
'Don't forget the coffee.'
No shit!
You didn't say that.
For Christ's sake,
Marty, it's a joke.
I know someone that
actually happened to, Marty.
-A joke.
-Gerry.
Hi. Have trouble
findin' the place?
No, I took a cab.
Timmy, this is Gerry.
We went to college together.
How you doin'? Nice to meet ya.
-Pleased to meet you.
-Can I get you a beer?
Um, no, just a Perrier.
That's French for club soda.
Club soda, yeah.
Couple of sandwiches too.
-Sure.
-Put it on my tab.
You ever plannin'
on payin' your tab?
Yeah, chief, got the winning
lottery ticket right here.
-What's the jackpot?
-Twelve million.
I don't think that'll cover it.
It'll cover your sex
change operation.
Nuts?
No, thank you.
So, you wanted to
talk about Will.
-Well, it seems to be going well.
-I think so.
Have you talked to him
at all about his future?
No, we haven't
gotten into that yet.
We're still bangin'
away at the past.
Maybe you should.
My phone's been ringing off
the hook with job offers.
What kind?
Cutting edge mathematics,
think tanks. The kind
of place where a mind
like Will's is given free rein.
That's great that
there are offers,
but I don't really think
he's ready for that.
I'm not sure you
understand, Sean.
-What don't I understand?
-Here you go, guys.
-Thanks, Tim.
-Yeah, thank you.
Just so you don't
get sticky fingers.
Tim, can you help us?
We're tryin' to settle a bet.
Uh-oh.
Ever heard of Jonas Salk?
Sure. Cured polio.
Ever heard of Albert Einstein?
Hey.
How about Gerald Lambeau?
Ever heard of him?
-No.
Thank you, Tim.
-So who won the bet?
-I did.
This isn't about me, Sean.
I'm nothing compared
to this young man.
You ever hear of Gerald Lambeau?
In 1905 there were
hundreds of professors
renown for their
study of the universe.
But it was a 26-year-old
Swiss patent clerk,
doing physics in his spare
time, who changed the world.
Can you imagine if Einstein
would have given that up...
just to get drunk with his
buddies in Vienna every night.
We all would have
lost something.
Tim would never
have heard of him.
Pretty dramatic, Gerry.
No, it isn't, Sean.
This boy has that gift.
He just doesn't
got the direction,
but we can give that to him.
Hey, Gerry,
in the 1960s, there
was a young man
graduated from
University of Michigan.
Did some brilliant
work in mathematics.
Specifically, bounded
harmonic functions.
Then he went on to Berkeley.
He was assistant professor.
Showed amazing potential.
Then he moved to Montana, and
he blew the competition away.
Yeah, so who was he?
Ted Kaczynski.
Haven't heard of him.
Hey, Timmy!
Yo!
Who's Ted Kaczynski?
Unabomber.
That's exactly what
I'm talking about.
-We gotta give this kid direction.
-Yeah...
He can contribute to the world,
and we can help him do that.
Direction's one thing.
Manipulation's another.
-Sean!
-We have to let him find...
I'm not sitting at
home every night
twisting my moustache
and hatching a...
hatching a plan to
ruin this boy's life!
I was doing advanced mathematics
when I was 18, and it
still took me over 20 years
to do something worthy
of a Field's medal.
Maybe he doesn't
want what you want.
There's more to life than
a fuckin' Field's medal.
This is too important, Sean,
and it's above personal rivalry.
Wait a minute. Wait
a minute, Gerry.
Let's talk about the boy.
Why don't we give him time
to figure out what he wants?
That's a wonderful theory, Sean.
It worked wonders
for you, didn't it?
Yeah, it did, you
arrogant fuckin' prick!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that I
came here today.
I came here out of courtesy.
I wanted to keep
you in the loop.
Nice to be in the loop.
The boy's in a meeting right now
I set up for him over at McNeil.
Well, Will,
I'm not exactly
sure what you mean.
We've already offered
you a position.
Nobody in this town works
without a retainer, guys.
You think you can find
somebody who does,
you have my blessin'.
But I think we all
know that person
is not gonna represent
you as well as I can.
Will, our offer
is $84,000 a year.
Retainer!
Retainer.
You want us...
to give you cash right now?
Whoa-ho-ho. Easy...
Now, I didn't say that.
Allegedly,
your situation,
for you,
would be concurrently
improved...
if I had...
$200 in my back
pocket right now.
I don't think I can...
Larry?
I've got $73.
Will you take a check?
Let me tell you somethin'.
You're suspect.
Yeah, you.
I don't know what your
reputation is in this town,
but after the shit you
tried to pull today,
you can bet I'll be
lookin' into you.
Now,
any business we have heretofore,
you can speak with my
aforementioned attorney.
Good day, gentlemen.
And until that day comes,
keep your ear to the grindstone.
How's it goin'?
Fine.
Yeah.
Good.
-Want some help?
-No!
Come on. Give me
one little peek,
No.
and we'll go to
the batting cages.
It is actually important
that I learn this.
-It's really important...
-All right.
-to me, okay?
All right.
Why don't we just
hang out here all day?
Yes, why don't we?
All right, Mr. Nosey Parker.
Seeing as you're intent
on breaking my balls,
let me ask you a question.
All right.
Do you have a
photographic memory?
I don't know. I just kind
of remember, you know?
I mean, how do you
remember your phone number?
You just do.
Have you studied
organic chemistry?
A little bit.
Oh, just for fun?
Yeah, for kicks.
Yeah, it's so much fun
studying organic chemistry.
Are you mad?
Have you completely
lost your mind?
Nobody studies it for fun.
It's not a necessity,
especially for someone like you.
-Someone like me?
-Yeah.
Someone who divides their
time, fairly evenly,
between batting cages and bars.
I would hardly say
it was a necessity.
You know, there are very
smart people here at Harvard.
Even they have to study,
because this is really hard.
And yet...
you do it so easily.
I don't understand.
I don't understand
how your mind works.
Did you play the piano?
I want to talk about this.
No, I'm trying to explain it to you.
Do you play the piano?
Yeah, a bit.
All right. So when you look at a
piano, you see Mozart.
I see 'Chopsticks'.
All right, well,
Beethoven, okay?
He looked at a piano,
and it just made sense to him.
He could just play.
So what are you saying?
You play the piano?
Not a lick. I look at a piano,
I see a bunch of keys, three
pedals and a box of wood.
But Beethoven, Mozart...
They saw it. They
could just play.
I couldn't paint you a picture.
I probably can't hit
the ball out of Fenway.
And I can't play the piano.
But you can do my O-chem
paper in under an hour.
Right. Well, I mean, when
it came to stuff like that,
I could always just play.
That's the best
I can explain it.
Come here.
I have to tell you something.
Well...
It's not fair.
What's not fair? What?
I've been here for four years,
and I've only just found you.
Well, you found me.
Are you awake?
No.
Yes, you are.
What?
I want you to come to
California with me.
You sure about that?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, but how do you know?
I don't know.
I just know.
Yeah, but how do you know?
I know, because...
I feel it.
Because that's a really
serious thing you're saying.
I... I know.
You could be in
California next week...
and you might find out something
about me you don't like.
Maybe you wish you
hadn't said that,
but you know it's such a serious
thing you can't take it back.
Now I'm stuck in California
with someone that doesn't
really want to be with me,
just wish they had a take-back.
A what?
What's a take-back?
I don't want a take-back.
I just want you to come
to California with me.
Well, I can't go to
California with you, so...
Why not?
Well, one, because I...
I got a job here.
And, two, because I live here.
Look, um,
if you don't love me, you
should just tell me, because I...
I'm not sayin' I don't love you.
Then why?
Why won't you come?
What are you so scared of?
What am I so scared of?
Well,
what aren't you scared of?
You live in this safe little
world where no one challenges you,
and you're scared shit
just to do anything that...
Don't tell me about my world.
I mean, you just want to have
your little fling
with the guy from the
other side of town.
Then you're gonna
go off to Stanford.
You're gonna marry
some rich prick...
who your parents
will approve of...
and just sit around with the
other trust fund babies...
and talk about how you
went slummin', too, once.
Why are you saying this?
What is your obsession
with this money?
My father died when I was 13,
and I inherited this money.
You don't think
every day I wake up,
and I wish I could give it back.
That I would give
it back in a second
if it meant I could have
one more day with him.
But I can't,
and that's my life,
and I deal with it.
So don't put your shit on me
when you're the
one that's afraid.
I'm afraid? What am I afraid of?
What the fuck am I afraid of?
You're afraid of me.
You're afraid that I
won't love you back.
You know what? I'm afraid too.
But fuck it, I want
to give it a shot.
At least I'm honest with you.
I'm not honest with you?
No, what about your 12 brothers?
All right.
No, you're not going.
You're not leaving.
What do you want to know?
That I don't have 12 brothers?
That I'm a fuckin' orphan?
-You don't want to hear that.
-I didn't know that.
You don't want to hear
that I got fuckin'
cigarettes put out on me
when I was a little kid.
-I didn't know that.
-That this isn't fuckin' surgery.
The mother fucker stabbed me.
You don't want to hear
that shit, Skylar!
-I do want to hear that.
-Don't tell me you want that shit!
I want to hear because
I want to help you.
-Because I want to be...
-Help me? What the fuck?
What do I got,
a fuckin' sign on my back
that says, 'Save me'?
-No.
-Do I look like I need that?
-No, I just want to be with you.
-Don't bullshit me!
I love you.
Don't bullshit me! Don't
you fuckin' bullshit me!
I love you.
I want to hear you say
that you don't love me.
Because if you say that...
then I won't call you...
and I won't be in your life.
I don't love you.
Most people never get to see
how brilliant they can be.
They don't find teachers
that believe in them.
They get convinced
they're stupid.
I hope you appreciate
what he's doing,
because I've seen how much
he enjoys working with you,
not against you.
Hello, Will.
Tom, can you get us some coffee?
Sure.
Now, let's see.
Good.
This is correct.
I see you used Maclaurin here.
Yeah, I don't know what
you call it, but...
This can't be right.
This would be very embarrassing.
-Did you ever consider...
-I'm pretty sure it's right.
Hey, look,
can we do this at Sean's office
from now on? Because I...
got to knock off
work to come here
and the commute is killin' me.
-Yeah, sure.
-Did you think of the possibility.
-That's right.
It's right.
Just take it home with you.
What happened at
the McNeil meeting?
I couldn't go. I had a date.
So I sent my chief negotiator.
On your own time, you can
do whatever you like, Will.
But when I set up a meeting
with my associates,
and you don't show up,
it reflects poorly on me.
-Then don't set up any more meetings.
-I won't.
I'll cancel 'em.
I'll give you a job myself.
I just wanted you to
see what was out there.
Maybe I don't want
to spend the rest
of my fuckin' life
explainin' shit to people.
I think you could show
me some appreciation.
A little appreciation?
Do you know how
easy this is for me?
Do you have any fuckin'
idea how easy this is?
This is a fuckin' joke.
I'm sorry you can't do this.
I really am...
Because I wouldn't have
to fuckin' sit here
and watch you fumble
around and fuck it up.
Then you'd have more
time to sit around
and get drunk
instead, wouldn't you?
You're right.
This is probably a
total waste of my time.
You're right, Will.
I can't do this proof,
but you can. And when it comes
to that, it's only about...
just a handful of
people in the world...
who can tell the difference
between you and me.
-But I'm one of them.
-Sorry.
Yeah, so am I.
Most days I wish
I never met you,
because then I could
sleep at night.
I didn't have to walk
around with the knowledge
that there was someone
like you out there.
I didn't have to watch
you throw it all away.
Bill, hold it.
Did you hear that?
Morgan!
If you're watchin' pornos
in my mom's room again,
I'm gonna give you
a fuckin' beatin'!
What's up, fellas?
Morgan, why don't you jerk
off in your own fuckin' house.
That's fuckin' filthy.
I don't have a V.C.R.
in my house.
Come on. Not in my glove.
I didn't use the glove.
That's my Little League glove.
What do you want me to do?
I mean, what's wrong with you?
You'll hump a baseball glove?
I just used it for clean-up.
Stop jerkin' off in
my mother's room.
Is there another V.C.R.
in the house?
It's just sad, bro.
So why do you
think I should work
for the National
Security Agency?
Well, you'd be working
on the cutting edge.
You'd be exposed to
the kind of technology
you wouldn't see anywhere else,
because we've classified it.
Super-string theory, chaos math,
-advanced algorithms.
-Code breaking.
That's one aspect of what we do.
Oh, come on. That
is what you do.
You guys handle 80% of
the intelligence workload.
You're seven times
the size of the C.I.A.
We don't like to brag
about that, Will,
but you're exactly right.
So the way I see it,
the question isn't:
'Why should you work
for the N.S.A.?'
The question is:
'Why shouldn't you?'
Why shouldn't I
work for the N.S.A.?
That's a tough one,
but I'll take a shot.
Say I'm workin' at the N.S.A.
and somebody puts
a code on my desk.
Something no one else can break.
Maybe I take a shot at
it and maybe I break it.
I'm real happy with myself
because I did my job well.
But maybe that code
was the location
of some rebel army in North
Africa or Middle East.
Once they have that location,
they bomb the village where
the rebels are hidin'.
Fifteen hundred people
that I never met,
never had no problem
with, get killed.
Now the politicians are saying,
'Send in the Marines
to secure the area,'
'cause they don't give a shit.
It won't be their kid
over there gettin' shot,
just like it wasn't them
when their number got called
'cause they were in
the National Guard.
It'll be some kid from
Southie over there
takin' shrapnel in the ass.
He comes back to find the
plant he used to work at...
got exported to the
country he got back from,
and the guy who put the shrapnel
in his ass got his old job...
'cause he'll work for 15 cents
a day and no bathroom breaks.
Meanwhile, he realizes
the only reason
he was over there in
the first place...
was so we could
install a government
that would sell us
oil at a good price.
Of course, the oil
companies used a skirmish
over there to scare up
domestic oil prices.
A cute little ancillary
benefit for them,
but it ain't helpin' my
buddy at 2.50 a gallon.
They're takin' their sweet time
bringin' the oil, of course.
Maybe they even took the liberty
to hire an alcoholic skipper,
who likes to drink Martinis
and fuckin' play slalom
with the icebergs.
It ain't too long till he
hits one, spills the oil...
and kills all the sea life
in the North Atlantic.
So now my buddy's out of work,
he can't afford to drive,
so he's walkin' to the
fuckin' job interviews...
which sucks because
the shrapnel in his ass
is givin' him
chronic haemorrhoids.
Meanwhile, he's starvin',
'cause every time he tries
to get a bite to eat,
the only blue plate
special they're servin'...
is North Atlantic scrod
with Quaker State.
So what did I think?
I'm holdin' out for
somethin' better.
I figure, fuck it.
While I'm at it, why
not just shoot my buddy,
take his job, give it
to his sworn enemy,
hike up gas prices, bomb a
village, club a baby seal,
hit the hash pipe and
join the National Guard?
I can be elected president.
You feel like
you're alone, Will?
What?
Do you have a soul mate?
Do I have a...? Define that.
Somebody who challenges you.
Uh, Chuckie.
No, Chuckie's family. He'd lie
down in fuckin' traffic for you.
I'm talking about someone
who opens up things for you,
touches your soul.
-I got... I got...
-Who?
I got plenty.
Well, name 'em.
Shakespeare, Nietzsche, Frost,
O'Connor, Kant, Pope, Locke...
That's great. They're all dead.
Not to me they're not.
You don't have a lot
of dialogue with them.
You can't give
back to them, Will.
Not without some serious
smelling salts and a heater.
That's what I'm saying.
You'll never have that kind
of relationship in a world...
where you're always afraid
to take the first step,
because all you see is
every negative thing
ten miles down the road.
You gonna take the
professor's side on this?
Don't give me a line of shit.
No.
I didn't want the job.
It's not about the job.
I don't care if you
work for the government.
But you can do
anything you want.
You are bound by nothing.
What are you passionate about?
What do you want?
There are guys who work their
entire life layin' brick...
so their kids have a chance
at the opportunities
you have here.
-I didn't ask for this.
-No.
You were born with it,
so don't cop out behind:
'I didn't ask for this.'
-What do you mean, cop out?
What's wrong with layin' brick?
-Nothing.
There's nothin' wrong. That's
somebody's home I'm buildin'.
Right. My dad laid brick, okay?
Busted his ass so I
could have an education.
Exactly. That's an
honourable profession.
What's wrong with
fixin' somebody's car?
Someone will get to work
the next day because of me.
That's honour in that.
Yeah, there is, Will.
There is honour in that.
There's honour in takin'
that 40-minute train ride...
so those college
kids could come in
in the morning and
their floors are clean.
And their waste baskets are empty.
That's real work.
That's right.
And that's honourable.
I'm sure that's why
you took that job.
I mean, for the honour of it.
I just have a little
question here.
You could be a janitor anywhere.
Why did you work at
the most prestigious
technical college in
the whole fuckin' world?
Why did you sneak
around at night
and finish other
people's formulas...
that only one or two
people in the world
could do and then lie about it?
'Cause I don't see a lot
of honour in that, Will.
So what do you really wanna do?
I wanna be a shepherd.
Really?
I wanna move up to Nashua,
get a nice little spread,
get some sheep and tend to them.
Maybe you should go do that.
What?
You know, if you're
gonna jerk off,
why don't you just do it
at home with a moist towel?
-You're chuckin' me?
-Yeah, get the fuck outta here.
-No, no, no, time's not up yet.
-Yeah, it is.
I'm not leavin'. No.
You're not gonna answer,
you're wastin' my time.
I thought we were friends.
What do you mean...
Playtime's over, okay?
Why are you kickin' me out, Sean?
I mean...
You're lecturin' me on life?
Look at you, you
fuckin' burnout.
What winds your clock?
Workin' with you.
Where's your soul mate?
You wanna talk about soul mates?
Where is she?
-Dead.
-That's right. She's fuckin' dead.
She fuckin' dies
and you just cash
in your chips and you walk away?
At least I played a hand.
You played a hand and you lost.
You lost a big fuckin' hand.
Some people will lose
a big hand like that
and have the sack
to ante up again.
Look at me.
What do you wanna do?
You and your bullshit.
You got a bullshit
answer for everybody.
But I ask you a
very simple question
and you can't give
me a straight answer,
because you don't know.
I'll see ya, Bo-peep.
-Fuck you.
-You're the shepherd.
Shepherd.
White little prick.
I just wanted to, you know, um,
call you up, uh,
before you left, um...
I've been takin' all these
jobs interviews and stuff,
so I'm not gonna be just
a construction worker.
Well, you know, I never
really cared about that.
Yeah.
I love you.
Will?
You take care.
Bye.
Will!
Will, that's it! We're done!
I'm sitting in your office
and the boy isn't here.
Well, it's ten past 5:00.
An hour and ten minutes late.
Well, if he doesn't show up
and I file a report
saying he wasn't here...
and he goes back to jail, he
won't be on my conscience.
Okay.
Fine.
What's up?
Thanks.
Ah!
God, that's good.
So how's your lady?
Ah, she's gone.
Gone? Gone where?
Med school.
Medical school in California.
-Really?
-Yeah.
When was this?
It was, like, a week ago.
That sucks.
So, uh, when are you
done with those meetings?
I think the week after I'm 21.
They gonna hook ya up
with a job or what?
Yeah, fuckin' sit in a room
and do long division
for the next 50 years.
Nah, probably make
some nice bank though.
I'm gonna be a fuckin' lab rat.
Better than this shit.
Way outta here.
What do I want a
way outta here for?
I mean, I'm gonna fuckin'
live here the rest of my life.
You know, be neighbours.
You know, have little kids.
Fuckin' take 'em to Little
League together up Foley Field.
Look, you're my best friend, so
don't take this the wrong way.
But in 20 years if
you're still livin' here,
comin' over to my house to
watch the Patriots games,
still workin' construction,
I'll fuckin' kill ya.
That's not a threat. That's a fact.
What the fuck are
you talkin' about?
Look,
you got something
none of us have.
Oh, come on! Why
is it always this?
I mean, I fuckin' owe it to
myself to do this or that.
What if I don't want to?
No, no, no. Fuck you. You
don't owe it to yourself.
You owe it to me,
'cause tomorrow I'm gonna
wake up and I'll be 50,
and I'll still be
doin' this shit.
That's all right. That's fine.
I mean, you're sittin' on
a winnin' lottery ticket.
You're too much of a
pussy to cash it in,
and that's bullshit.
'Cause I'd do fuckin'
anything to have what you got.
So would any of
these fuckin' guys.
Be an insult to us if you're
still here in 20 years.
Hangin' around here is a
fuckin' waste of your time.
-You don't know that.
-I don't?
-No. You don't know that.
-Oh, I don't know that.
Let me tell you what I do know.
Every day I come by your
house, and I pick you up.
We go out and have a few drinks
and few laughs, and it's great.
You know what the best
part of my day is?
It's for about ten seconds:
from when I pull up to the curb
and when I get to your door.
'Cause I think maybe
I'll get up there
and I'll knock on the door
and you won't be there.
No 'good-bye', no 'see ya later'.
No nothing.
You just left.
I don't know much,
but I know that.
This is a disaster, Sean.
I brought you in here because
I wanted you to help
me with the boy,
-not to run him out.
-I know what I'm doing with the boy.
I don't care if you have
a rapport with the boy!
I don't care if you have a few
laughs, even at my expense.
But don't you dare undermine
what I'm trying to do here.
Undermine?
This boy is at a
fragile point right now.
I do understand. He is at a fragile point.
Okay? He's got problems.
What problems does
he have, Sean?
That he's better off as a janitor,
that he is better off in jail?
Better hanging out with a
bunch of retarded gorillas?
Why do you think he
does that, Gerry?
You have any fuckin' clue why?
He can handle the problems.
He can handle the work.
He obviously handled you.
Gerry, Listen. Listen to me.
Why is he hiding?
Why doesn't he trust anybody?
Because the first thing
that happened to him,
he was abandoned by the people
who were supposed to
love him the most.
Come on. Don't give
me that Freudian crap.
Oh, no. Listen Gerry,
why does he hang out with those
retarded gorillas,
as you call them?
Because any one of them,
if he asked them to,
would take a fucking
bat to your head. Okay?
-That's called loyalty.
-Yeah, that's very touching.
And, who's he handling?
He pushes people away
before they have a
chance to leave him.
It's a defence
mechanism, all right?
For 20 years, he's been
alone because of that.
If you push him right now,
it's gonna be the same
thing all over again.
And I'm not gonna let
that happen to him.
-Don't you do that, Sean.
-What?
Don't you do that. Don't
infect him with the idea
that it's okay to quit, that
it's okay to be a failure.
Because it's not okay, Sean!
And if you're angry at
me for being successful,
for being what you
could have been...
-I'm not angry at you.
-Oh, yes, you're angry at me, Sean.
You resent me,
but I'm not gonna apologize
for any success I've had.
You're angry at me for doing
what you could have done!
But ask yourself,
Sean, ask yourself...
ask yourself, if you want
Will to feel that way,
if you want him to
feel like a failure?
You arrogant shit!
That's why I don't come
to the goddamn reunions,
'cause I can't stand
that look in your eye.
You know, that condescending,
embarrassed look.
Oh, come on, Sean.
You think I'm a failure.
I know who I am.
I'm proud of what I do.
It was a conscious choice.
I didn't fuck up!
And you and your cronies think
I'm some sort of pity case.
You and your kiss-ass chorus
following you around going, 'The
Field's medal!', The Field's Medal!'
Why are you still so
fuckin' afraid of failure?
It's about my medal, isn't it?
Oh, God, I could go home and get it for you.
You can have it.
Oh, please don't. You know what!
Shove the medal up your
fuckin' ass, all right?
'Cause I don't give a
shit about your medal,
because I knew you before
you were a mathematical god,
when you were
pimple-faced and homesick
and didn't know what side
of the bed to piss on.
Yeah, you were
smarter than me then
and you're smarter than me now.
So don't blame me for how your
life turned out. It's not my fault.
I don't blame you!
It's not about you!
You mathematical dick!
It's about the boy!
He's a good kid! And I
won't see you fuck him up
like you're tryin' to
fuck up me right now.
I won't see you make him
feel like a failure too!
He won't be a failure!
But if you push him, Gerry,
if you ride him...
I am what I am today
because I was pushed
and because I learned
to push myself.
He's not you! You get that!
-I can come back.
-No, come in. Uh...
I was just leaving.
A lot of that stuff goes back
a long way between me and him.
You know.
Not about you.
What is that?
This is your file.
I have to send it back to
the judge for evaluation.
Oh.
Hey, you're not gonna
fail me, are you?
What's it say?
Wanna read it?
Why?
Have you had any, uh,
experience with that?
Twenty years of counselling.
Yeah, I've seen some
pretty awful shit.
I mean, have you had any
experience with that?
Personally?
Yeah.
Yeah, I have.
It sure ain't good.
My father was an alcoholic.
Mean fuckin' drunk.
He'd come home hammered,
lookin' to whale on somebody.
So I'd provoke him so he
wouldn't go after my
mother and little brother.
Interesting nights
when he wore his rings.
-Yeah.
-He used to just put a...
a wrench, a stick and a belt
on the table. Just
say, 'Choose'.
Well, I gotta go
with the belt there.
I used to go with the wrench.
Why the wrench?
'Cause fuck him, that's why.
Your foster father?
Yeah.
So, uh, what is it, like,
Will has an attachment disorder?
Is it all that stuff?
Fear of abandonment?
Is that why I...
Is that why I broke
up with Skylar?
I didn't know you had.
Yeah, I did.
-You wanna talk about it?
-No.
Hey, Will,
I don't know a lot.
You see this?
All this shit?
It's not your fault.
Yeah, I know that.
Look at me, son.
It's not your fault.
I know.
No.
It's not your fault.
I know.
No, no, you don't.
It's not your fault.
I know.
All right.
It's not your fault.
Don't fuck with me.
Don't fuck with me, all right?
Don't fuck with
me, Sean, not you.
It's not your fault.
My God...
My God! I'm so sorry! My God!
Fuck them, okay?
Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm Will Hunting.
I'm here about a position.
Could you just have
a seat for a moment?
Yes, there's a Mr. Hunting
in the lobby.
Which one did you take?
I was over at McNeil.
It's one of the jobs the
professor set me up with.
I haven't told him yet,
but I went down there
and talked to my boss...
My new boss. He seemed
like a good guy.
Is that what you want?
Yeah, you know, I think so.
Well, good for you.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Time's up.
So that's... so that's it?
So we're done?
Yeah, that's it.
You're done.
You're a free man.
Well, um,
I just want you to
know, Sean, that...
You're welcome, Will.
So, you know, I hope we
keep in touch, you know.
Yeah, me too.
I'll be travelin' around a bit.
It'll be a little
hard, but, uh...
I've got an answering machine
at the college I'll
be checking in with.
So, here's the number.
You call that. I'll get
back to you right away.
Yeah, you know, I
figured I'm just gonna...
put my money back on the table
and see what kind
of cards I get.
You do what's in your heart, son.
You'll be fine.
Thank you, Sean.
Thank you, Will.
Hey, does this violate the
patient-doctor relationship?
Naw. Only if you grab my ass.
Take care.
You too.
Yeah.
Hey.
Good luck, son.
Two beers.
What's up? Did you guys go?
No. I had to talk him down.
Why didn't you yoke him?
Little Morgan's got a
lot of scrap to him.
People try to whip
his ass every week.
Fuckin' kid won't back down.
What are you sayin' about me?
Was I talkin' to you?
None of your fuckin' business.
-Go get me a beer.
-I ordered two beers!
-Hey, ass hole.
-What, bitch?
Happy birthday.
Thought we forgot, huh, bitch?
-Come on!
-I'm goin'. I'm goin'.
All right. Who's first?
-Come on, mother fucker!
-Who's first?
Here's your present.
-Come on, bro.
-What?
Well, we knew you
had to get back
and forth to Cambridge
for your new job.
I knew I wasn't gonna fuckin'
drive you every day, so...
Morgan wanted to
get you a 'T' pass.
That's not what I was sayin'!
But, uh,
you're 21 now.
You're legally allowed to drink,
so we figured the best
thing for ya was a car.
How do you like it?
This is like...
It's the ugliest fuckin' car
I've ever seen in my life.
-Come on, brother.
-How'd you guys do this?
You know,
me and Bill scraped
together the parts, and...
Morgan was out panhandlin'
for change every day.
I had the router to
do all the bodywork.
Yeah, I have a fuckin'
job, too, brother.
Guy's been up my
ass for two years
about a job. I had to let
him help with the car.
So you finally got
a job, huh, Morgan?
Yeah, had one. Now
I'm fucked again.
So what is it? A lawn mower?
What do ya got?
It's a straight fuckin' six.
Me and Bill rebuilt this
engine ourselves here.
It's a good car. The engine's good.
Engine's good.
Happy 21, Will.
Happy 21, brother.
Hi.
Come on in.
Sean, I, um...
Me too, Gerry.
Yeah. Good.
I heard you're takin' some time.
Yeah.
Travel a little bit,
maybe write.
So where are you going?
India and...
China...
and Baltimore.
You know when you'll be back?
Oh.
I got this flyer the other day.
It says, uh, class of '72 is
having a reunion in six months.
Yeah, I got one of those too.
Why don't you come?
I'll buy ya a drink.
The drinks at those
things are free.
I know, Gerry. I
was being ironical.
How about a drink right now?
Yeah. It's a good idea.
Come on. This one's on me.
I got the winner
right here, pal.
Yes, sir, this is the one.
This is my ticket to paradise.
Sean, do you know
what the odds are
against winning the lottery?
-What? Four to one?
-About 30 million to one.
I still have a shot, you know?
Yes,
just about as big
chance as you being hit
by lightning here on
the staircase right now.
It's a possibility too. I mean,
32 million. If you
look at the size...
Will!
Will?
He's not there.
Sean,
if the professor
calls about that job,
just tell him sorry,
I had to go see about a girl.
Will.
Son of a bitch.
He stole my line.